Ayush Sinha

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India



linkedin.com/in/ayushsinha012



ayush.suvi@gmail.com

Summary

An tech enthusiast with a demonstrated history of working in the product industry. Skilled in React JS, NodeJS, ExpressJs, MongoDB, Javascript, HTML, CSS. Strong application development professional having 4 years of total experience with a Bachelor of Engineering focused in Telecommunications Engineering from BMS Institute of Technology and Management.

Experience



Associate Consultant

Neudesic

Aug 2019 - Present (10 months +)

I am working here as an Custom Application Developer. I have worked on different domain ranging from Product development, EDI Process to Analyst Salesforce development etc. My major work here included

1. Internal Product Development: To develop an internal resource management application, for allocation of resources in different project by mapping skills and project requirement, recruitment etc.

I was tasked with leading the complete application front end UI Development using ReactJS, HTML,CSS and Material UI.

- 2. EDI Process Support Analyst: This project was mainly focused on performing 810s,910s,940s process imports and exports, performing web pool configuration and validating data. I lead the project for a short duration and performed training for onboarding of different devlopers.
- 3. Salesforce Development: To create custom app according to customer requirements and need. I was tasked to create custom app, custom object, data modelling, lightning application, connected application, create api for console application etc. Worked on SOQL, SOSL, DML, C#, .NET etc.

Founder-CEO

CONTRIV

Mar 2017 - Present (3 years 3 months +)

I formed this company targeting to resolve all kinds of persisting issues through means of software, robotics, Virtual Reality etc.

We worked on various projects, majorly on developing a product focused on providing micro credit to a targeted group of audience through means of mobile application.

My major work included to form a business model, build up a wholesome team ranging from Development to Legal and getting funding. Technically i worked as an Front end developer for the application using React Native

NodeJS Developer

CONTRIV

Jan 2020 - May 2020 (5 months)

Task App Manager: The app focused on organizing different task with options of Priority, Timeline, Assignee's etc. My major task included developing the completed back end, with developing REST API's using Express.JS ,taking care of Authorization and authentication at api levels, designing and developing database using MongoDB and hosting it in HEROKU.

Education



BMS Institute of Technology and Management

Bachelor of Engineering, Telecommunications Engineering 2015 - 2019

Licenses & Certifications

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 7 Programmer - NIIT Technologies Limited



Honors & Awards



NeuSpot Award - Neudesic

Jan 2020

For enthusiastic participation in all technical and non technical activities that included Technical interviewer in hiring ,fun activity conduction etc.



NeuSpot Award - Neudesic

May 2020

For outstanding contribution in ongoing project and performing vital operation to avert operation breakdown at a particular instance by successfully coordinating with support team and team members

Skills

React.js • Node.js • MERN Stack • Web Design • Web Development • C# • JavaScript • Express.js • MongoDB • salesforce